Bonowitz, Abraham J.; Papers apap186
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Audio Visual Materials, 1977-2013; 12; 3.79 cubic ft.
  - Moratorium on Death Penalty, 2002 January 21 (Oversized 4, Vhs 2)
  - Mr. Death: Rise and Fall of Fred A. Leuchter, Jr., 2000 (Oversized 4, Vhs 3)
  - Mt. Ennon Baptist Church, 2012 December 9 (Oversized 6, Cd 25)
  - MVFR Logo, Undated (Oversized 8, Floppy-disk 39)
  - Nancy Grace, 2006 May 4 (Oversized 6, Cd 26)
  - NCADP, 2004 (Oversized 7, Mini-dv 9)
  - NCADP Annual Conference CDROM, 2005 October 27 (Oversized 6, Cd 27)
  - NCADP Annual Conference CDROM, 2006 October 27-29 (Oversized 6, Cd 28)
  - NCADP Clippings, Undated (Oversized 6, Cd 29)
  - News Tape, Undated (Oversized 4, Vhs 4)
  - NJADP 1/5, Undated (Oversized 6, Cd 30)
  - NJADP 2/5, Undated (Oversized 6, Cd 31)
  - NJADP 3/5, Undated (Oversized 6, Cd 32)
  - NJADP 4/5, Undated (Oversized 6, Cd 33)
  - NJADP 5/5, Undated (Oversized 6, Cd 34)
  - NJADP Victory Celebration, 2008 March 1 (Oversized 6, Cd 35)
  - Not In My Name Performances by the Living Theatre in Duffy Square, NYC, 1997 May 28 (Oversized 4, Vhs 5)
  - Not In Our Name! Amnesty International, 2008 (Oversized 6, Cd 36)
  - Odell Barnes Defense, Undated (Oversized 4, Vhs 6)
  - Ohio Journey of Hope, 2003 (Oversized 4, Vhs 7)
  - Ohio Journey of Hope, Pictures [1 of 2], 2003 October 26 (Oversized 6, Cd 37)
  - Ohio Journey of Hope, Pictures [1 of 2], 2003 October 26 (Oversized 6, Cd 38)
  - One. For. Ten., 2013 (Oversized 6, Cd 39)
  - Oregon's Death Penalty: An Interview with Sister Helen Prejean Author, "Dead Man Walking", 2011 October 20 (Oversized 6, Cd 40)
  - Out of the Silence: Fighting for Human Rights, 1992 (Oversized 4, Vhs 8)
  - Parker Quanell X, Undated (Oversized 8, Floppy-disk 9)
  - Peace in the Park, A Project of Pathways to Peace, Undated (Oversized 4, Vhs 9)
  - Pete and Fay, 1977 September 24 (Oversized 7, Mini-dv 11)
  - Phone Calls, Undated (Oversized 7, Mini-dv 10)
  - Plenary I Herdesty [2 of 2], Undated (Oversized 7, Mini-dv 4)
  - Plenary I Johnson, McAndrew, Herdesty [1 of 2], Undated (Oversized 7, Mini-dv 3)
  - Portland, 1995 November 11 (Oversized 9, Mini-dv 31)
  - Postcard and Other Images, Undated (Oversized 8, Zip-disk 54)
  - Pragmatic Abolitionism, Herb Haines (.txt file), Undated (Oversized 8, Floppy-disk 7)
  - Rancho Aradillo Recording Service - Steve Earle 7th Annual Fast & Vigil to Abolish the Death Penalty, 2000 July 18 (Oversized 6, Cd 41)
  - Randy Rhodes Show, Undated (Oversized 7, Mini-dv 12)
  - Re: Amnesty Group Problem, Undated (Oversized 9, Mini-dv 29)
  - Re: Amnesty Group Problem, Undated (Oversized 9, Mini-dv 30)
  - Reality News Network Cuba Uncut, 2000 May- June (Oversized 4, Vhs 10)
  - Reality News Network Death Penalty 60 Minutes, Undated (Oversized 4, Vhs 11)
  - Reason to Believe, 1995 (Oversized 7, Cassette 8)
  - Sat Openny NCADP, 2009 (Oversized 7, Mini-dv 5)
  - Sheppard, 2000 March 17 (Oversized 4, Vhs 12)
  - Sister Helen Prejean, 2006 February (Oversized 4, Vhs 13)
  - Sister Helen Prejean, 2006 March (Oversized 4, Vhs 14)
  - Small Box, 2009 November 7 (Oversized 6, Cd 45)
  - Sr. Margaret Letter (Fax), 1998 February 25 (Oversized 8, Floppy-disk 21)
  - Step by Step, 1998 (Oversized 6, Cd 42)
  - Step by Step, 1998 (Oversized 6, Cd 43)
  - Steve Earl, 2004 (Oversized 6, Cd 44)
  - Steve Earle - Washington, D.C., 2001 July 1 (Oversized 9, Video-tape 1)
  - Steve Earle Fast & Vigil, 2004 (Oversized 7, Mini-dv 6)
  - Steve Earle, CUADP, 2001 July 1 (Oversized 4, Vhs 15)
  - Still Killing Academics for the Abolition of Capital Punishment, A Film Directed by Adan Nieto, 2011 (Oversized 9, Cd 2)
  - Sundance Selects, 2011 October 27 (Oversized 6, Cd 46)
  - Tailspin Presentation, Undated (Oversized 6, Cd 49)
  - Talk of the Nation, Undated (Oversized 7, Cassette 9)
  - Talking About the Death Penalty, 1999 (Oversized 5, Vhs 1)
  - Tallahassee, WUFT, 2001 November 27 (Oversized 5, Vhs 2)
  - Tangible Vision, 2002 (Oversized 5, Vhs 3)
  - Terre Haute, 2001 May 16 (Oversized 5, Vhs 4)
  - The Awful Truth, 2000 May 24 (Oversized 5, Vhs 5)
  - The Closure Myth, Inner Light Media, Undated (Oversized 5, Vhs 6)
  - The Empty Chair: Death Penalty Yes or No, Undated (Oversized 6, Cd 48)
  - The Exonerated, 2009 October (Oversized 6, Cd 16)
  - The Frame - Samuel Reese Sheppard, Undated (Oversized 6, Cd 50)
  - The Frame - Samuel Reese Sheppard, Undated (Oversized 6, Cd 51)
  - The Freedom Files - The Death Penalty Freedom to Live a Film by Robert Greenwald, ACLU, 2007 (Oversized 6, Cd 52)
  - The Life Penalty Directed by David Quint, 2008 (Oversized 6, Cd 53)
  - The Life Penalty Directed by David Quint, 2008 (Oversized 6, Cd 54)
  - The Next Step News From the Front Lines of Abolition, Undated (Oversized 5, Vhs 7)
  - The Promise, The Real News Network, Undated (Oversized 6, Cd 55)
  - The Second Execution of Romell Broom by Michael Verhoeven, Undated (Oversized 6, Cd 56)
  - The Story of Harold Wilson: Convicted of Triple Murder, Sentenced to Die, Exonerated after 17 Years I Prison - Democracy Now!, 2005 December 20 (Oversized 6, Cd 57)
  - Time Out: Perspectives on New Jersey's Death Penalty, 2002 (Oversized 5, Vhs 8)
  - Too Flawed to Fix, The Illinois Death Penalty Experience, Peace Productions, Undated (Oversized 6, Cd 58)
  - TX Event Flyer (Calendar) Do What You Can Helen Flyer 5/21, Undated (Oversized 8, Floppy-disk 19)
  - United Farm Workers of America "No Grapes", Undated (Oversized 5, Vhs 9)
  - United States of Alec, 2013 (Oversized 6, Cd 59)
  - Video Traffic Class, Inc., Undated (Oversized 5, Vhs 10)
  - Virginia Journey of Hope, 2006 October (Oversized 5, Vhs 11)
  - Visions of Life: Art Out of Death Row, 1999 February 9 (Oversized 8, Floppy-disk 26)
  - Voicemail, 2001 April 7 (Oversized 7, Mini-dv 13)
  - Voices of Freedom, 1992 (Oversized 7, Cassette 10)
  - West Wing - "Take This Sabbath Day", 2000 February 9 (Oversized 5, Vhs 12)
  - What I've Learned About US Foreign Policy By Frank Dorrel, Undated (Oversized 5, Vhs 13)
  - Word Backup, 2001 January 17 (Oversized 8, Zip-disk 47)
  - Your Turn Exonerated, 2005 July 28 (Oversized 5, Vhs 14)
  - Your Voice Counts Turning Lobbying Upside Down, Undated (Oversized 5, Vhs 15)
- Amenesty International, 1980-2015; 13; 2 cubic ft.
  Abe Bonowitz has been an active member of Amnesty International since 1989. This series allows a small view into what Amnesty International is advocating for when it pertains to the death penalty.
  - The Death Penalty in the USA, 1980 November (Box 1 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 1)
  - Amnesty International report, 1987 July 8 (Box 1 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 2)
  - Human Rights Quarterly Vol. 11 no. 2, 1989 May (Box 1 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 3)
  - Human Rights Quarterly Vol. 11 no. 3, 1989 August (Box 1 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 4)
  - Human Rights Quarterly Vol. 12 no. 1, 1990 February (Box 1 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 5)
  - Human Rights Quarterly Vol. 12 no. 4, 1990 November (Box 1 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 6)
  - Amnesty International Report, 1991 (Box 1 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 7)
  - Amnesty International Report, 1992 (Box 1 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 8)
  - "Amnesty International and the Death Penalty", 1979 (Box 1 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 9)
  - Amnesty International Report, 1993 (Box 1 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 10)
  - The Death Penalty in Wartime: Arguments, 1994 January (Box 1 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 11)
  - USA: Open letter to the President on the Death Penalty, 1994 January (Box 1 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 12)
  - Jesus Manuel Corrales Preemptive Death Penalty Case Report for Amnesty International USA, 1994 May 9 (Box 1 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 13)
  - Amnesty International The Imposition of the Death Penalty, 1994 June (Box 1 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 14)
  - Amnesty International Report, 1994 (Box 1 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 15)
  - "'Dissapearances and Political Killings' Human Rights Crisis of the 1990s", 1994 (Box 1 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 16)
  - Enrique R. Valenzuels Cover Letter and Resume AIUSA Board Application, 2004 (Box 1 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 17)
  - Amnesty International Report, 1995 (Box 1 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 18)
  - Amnesty International Report, 1996 (Box 1 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 19)
  - George laRoche to Ms. Rose re: Policy Issues, 1996 (Box 1 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 20)
  - Programs and Materials Related to Amnesty International Events During the Atlanta Olympics, 1996 (Box 1 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 21)
  - AIUSA Board of Directors Election Summary, 1997 (Box 1 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 22)
  - Manual for Amnesty Interantional USA Board of Directors (1 of 2), 1997 (Box 1 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 23)
  - Manual for Amnesty International USA Board of Directors (2 of 2), 1997 (Box 1 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 24)
  - Lethal Injection: The Medical Technology of Execution, 1998 January 30 (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 1)
  - AIUSA Children's Rights News, 1999 Spring (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 2)
  - National Weekend of Faith in Action Guidebook, 2000 July (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 3)
  - Study Guide: The Death Penalty in America 25 Years After Gregg v. Georgia, 2000 (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 4)
  - Program to Abolish the Death Penalty National Weekend of Faith in Action, 2001 August (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 5)
  - AIUSA Program to Abolish the Death Penalty National Weekend of Faith in Action, 2001 October 12-14 (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 6)
  - "Activists Toolkit" Made by Terre Haute Abolition Network With A.I. Materials, 2003 June 23 (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 7)
  - AIUSA Volunteer Leadership Resources, 2003 July (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 8)
  - National Weekend of Faith in Action Resources, 2003 August (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 9)
  - AIUSA Southern Regional Conference, 2003 November 7 (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 10)
  - Human Rights Awards Dinner Invite, 2003 November 20 (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 11)
  - Amnesty International Newsletter, 2003 December (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 12)
  - "Amnesty In Action" Pamphlet, 2003 (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 13)
  - Amnesty International Program "Rhythm n' Rights", 2003 (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 14)
  - National Weekend of Faith in Action on the Death Penalty Organizing Packet, 2003 (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 15)
  - "React: 2003/2004" Basic field Manual (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 16)
  - "React: 2003/2004" Basic field Manual (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 17)
  - Amnesty International Letter, 2004 March 9 (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 18)
  - Group 159 News, 2004 March - April (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 19)
  - Vigilant Justice, 2004 (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 20)
  - Urgent Action Newsletter, 2004 May - September (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 21)
  - National Weekend of Faith in Action Newsletter, 2004 August (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 22)
  - The 2004 National Weekend of Faith in Action on the Death Penalty, 2004 October 22-24 (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 23)
  - Group 159 News, 2004 November - December (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 24)
  - Summary Report on National Weekend of Faith in Action on the Death Penalty, 2004 (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 25)
  - AIUSA Volunteer Leadership Contact Sheet, 2004-2005 (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 26)
  - Volunteer Leadership Handbook, 2004-2005 (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 27)
  - Florida Statewide Meeting Program, 2005 February 19 (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 28)
  - Annual General Meeting Resolutions Packet, 2005 February (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 29)
  - Program to Abolish the Death Penalty National Steering Committee Meeting Materials, 2005 April 8 (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 30)
  - "No Excuses. No Exceptions." Annual General Meeting Program and Documents, 2005 April 8-10 (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 31)
  - The Death Penalty Worldwide: Developments in 2004, 2005 April (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 32)
  - National Weekend of Faith in Action Resources, 2005 August (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 33)
  - National Weekend of Faith in Action, 2005 October 21-22 (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 34)
  - A Beacon of Hope in a Troubled World, 2005 (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 35)
  - Amnesty International Reform Slate, 2005 (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 36)
  - Faith in Action Resource Guidebook, 2005 (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 37)
  - Save the Day Flier for National Weekend of Fatih in Action on the Death Penalty, 2005 (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 38)
  - "The Rest of Their Lives: Life Without Parole for Child Offenders", 2005 (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 39)
  - National Human Rights Priority Settings Worksheet, 2005-2006 (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 40)
  - AIUSA Letter Concerning "Stonewalled" Campaign, 2006 March 23 (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 41)
  - "Human Rights at High Volume" Annual General Meeting Program, 2006 April 28-30 (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 42)
  - The Death Penalty in America Thirty Years after Gregg v. Georgia Amnesty International Grassroots Organizing Kit, 2006 (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 43)
  - The Death Penalty in America Thirty Years after Gregg v. Georgia Study Guide, 2006 (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 44)
  - Amnesty International Magazine, 2008 Fall (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 45)
  - Activist's Guide for National Teach-In Week for Troy Davis, 2009 September 21-27 (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 46)
  - Death Penalty Awareness Week Resource Kit, 2010 January (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 47)
  - "Shine a Light: 50 Years", 2010 Winter (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 48)
  - "Rise Up Be The Change" Mid Atlantic Regional Conference Resources and Materials, 2011 November 11-14 (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 49)
  - AIUSA Capri Report to the Board, 2014 July (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 50)
  - "From Moment to Movement" 2015 Regional Conference (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 51)
  - Hope for Humanity Year in Review, 2015 (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 52)
  - Tricia Hart Personalized Membership Mailing to A. Bonowitz, 2015 (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 53)
  - Year-End Fundraising Drive Letter, 2015 (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 54)
  - "A Toast to Our Activists" Program, undated (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 55)
  - AIUSA Assorted Organizational Contacts and Resources, undated (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 56)
  - Amnesty International Internship Program, undated (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 57)
  - Amnesty International: Lethal Injustice, undated (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 58)
  - Amnesty International Report, undated (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 59)
  - Enough Killing, Abolish the Death Penalty Pamphlet, undated (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 60)
  - "From Violence to Healing: Ending the Death Penalty" Flyer, undated (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 61)
  - "No More Killing: Abolish the Death Penalty" Flyer, undated (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 62)
  - "Stop the Execution of Reggie Clemmons" Flyer, undated (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 63)
  - "The AIUSA Organizing Model, Or: From Snowflake to Avalanche", undated (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 64)
  - USA: The Death Penalty Amnesty International Briefing, undated (Box 2 (13-Amenesty International), Folder 65)